一千年前…
一群織布工組織了一個秘密的刺客集團
他們通過暗殺活動使瀕臨崩潰的世界恢復秩序
他們自稱為「兄弟會」
六個星期前…
生日快樂，親愛的賈妮絲
ALL: (SINGING) Happy birthday, dear Janice
祝你生日快樂！
Happy birthday to you!
正在過生日的是我那得了厭食癥的老闆
WESLEY: It's my anorexic boss' birthday.
(ALL CHATTERING)
這意味著各個辦公室的人都在某種程度的壓力下
This means there's a certain amount of inter-office pressure
被迫站到會議桌邊
to stand around the conference table
一邊吃著垃圾食品一邊假裝崇拜她
eating crappy food and pretending to worship her.
真好吃
That's so good.
要在整整五分鐘裡忘記賈妮絲對大家的殘酷壓迫
WESLEY: Acting for five minutes like Janice doesn't make all our lives miserable
這是我一天裡最困難的工作
is the hardest work I'll do all day.
我的工作頭銜是賬戶經理
My job title is account manager.
以前我的工作是叫做賬戶服務代表
I used to be called an account service representative,
可是有個顧問說我們需要的是管理客戶
but a consultant told us we needed to manage our clients
而不是給他們服務
and not service them.
(TRAIN RUMBLING)
(MOANING)
我有個女朋友我對她既沒有管理也沒有服務
I have a girlfriend whom I neither manage nor service.
我最要好的朋友巴裡正在一張宜家牌餐桌上操她
That's my best friend, Barry, fucking her on an IKEA kitchen table
那張桌子是我用很實惠的價錢淘來的
I picked up for a really good price.
我發現最近我很難在乎什麼事了
I'm finding it hard to care about anything these days.
事實上，我唯一在乎的事就是我對任何事情都關心不起來
In fact, the only thing I do care about is the fact that I can't care about anything.
真的，這讓我很擔心
Seriously. It worries me.
我叫韋斯利·吉布森
My name is Wesley Gibson.
韋斯利·吉布森 - 沒有結果
我出生才七天爸爸就扔下媽媽跑了
My dad walked out on my mom when I was seven days old.
有時我想，也許他曾經望著寶貝兒子的藍眼睛，捫心自問：
Sometimes I wonder if he ever looked into my baby blues eyes and asked himself,
我就是這個21世紀頭號廢柴的老爸嗎？
"Did I just father the most insignificant asshole of the 21st century?"
好，要是你能在28號以前把托賣的貨物給我… 對
Well, if you could get me the consignment to me by the 28th... Yeah.
你面前有號碼嗎？
Do you have the numbers in front of you?
別緊張
MR x: Relax.
如果出現的是你的名字你早就死了
If your name had come up, you'd be dead already.
我們最近有一些意外的損失
We've had some unexpected losses recently.
我們想知道
We'd like to know
我們的對頭是從哪裡搞到軍火的
where our competitor is getting his munition.
很乾淨
It's clean.
什麼意思？
Meaning?
意思就是沒法追查來源
Meaning it's untraceable.
你的對頭非常聰明
Your competitor's very smart.
(HIGH-PITCHED WHIRRING)
臥倒！
Get down!
(BULLETS WHOOSHING)
(ExCLAIMS)
我操
Fuck it.
(HEART BEATING)
(HEART BEATING RAPIDLY)
(SCREAMING)
(GLASS SHATTERING)
(GUN FIRES)
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
沒有人能脫離兄弟會，「十字架」
No one leaves the Fraternity, Cross.
我對兄弟會有了新的看法
CROSS ON PHONE: I have a new perspective on the Fraternity.
小心點
MR x: Careful.
你不可能毀掉存在了一千年的組織
You don't destroy something that's been around for a thousand years.
組織已經毀了他破壞了法典
CROSS: It's already destroyed. He broke the code.
我不能不阻止
I have to stop this.
- 真的？- 你明白
- Really? - You know this.
那為什麼你不肯親自來面對我？
So why don't you face me yourself?
千萬別派小綿羊來殺大灰狼
Never send sheep to kill a wolf.
他們只是幌子
CROSS: They were just the decoys.
再見，X先生
Goodbye, Mr x.
(WHOOSHING)
(GRUNTS)
(BACKWARD VOICES)
(CLICKING)
千萬別派小綿羊來殺大灰狼
MR x: Never send sheep to kill a wolf.
他們只是幌子
They were just the decoys.
韋斯利！
CATHY: Wesley!
怎麼啦？
What is it?
什麼怎麼啦？聽啊
What do you mean, "What is it"? Listen.
(RUMBLING)
這麼吵，你叫我怎麼睡得著？
Well, how am I suppose to sleep with all that fucking racket?
老是被這鬼東西吵醒我們到底什麼時候搬家？
When are we gonna move so we don't have to wake up to that shit?
我倒是有點喜歡這聲音
I kind of like it.
它可以淹沒你那討厭的破嗓門
WESLEY: It helps to drown out the sound of your annoying, fucking voice.
現在求求你，讓我睡吧
Now, please, let me sleep.
你到底有沒有考慮過我們談的事？
Have you even thought about our talk?
嗯
Yes.
哪一次？
Which one?
好極了，好極了
Perfect. That's perfect.
給安娜貝爾餵食
Feed Annabelle.
(MEOWS)
(RUMBLING)
(ROCK MuSIC PLAYING)
(BRAKES SCREECHING)
對不起
Sorry.
哦，我的天哪
(LAUGHING) Oh, my fucking God.
但願你桌上那個東西不是我要的結算報告
I hope that's not my billing report sitting on your desk.
真像供桌上的一泡大便
Holy shit on an altar, it is.
一小時內把報告交到我桌上
I want that report on my desk in one hour.
好吧，各位，我們還要加班一小時…
Okay, everybody, we're all gonna stay an extra hour...
想聽點慘事嗎？
WESLEY: Want to hear something sad?
我必須使用人體工程學鍵盤才能讓重複性壓抑的危害不至於太大
I need an ergonomic keyboard to keep my repetitive stress injury in check.
我的重複性工作多得讓我壓抑真他媽的慘
Just the fact that I repeat something enough that it causes me stress is fucking sad.
幹得好，哥們，看見巴裡沒有？
Nice job, dude. You seen Barry?
他又去看牙醫了
He had to go to the dentist. Again.
Yes!
(MOANING)
巴裡！
Barry!
你說他們這裡有沒有事後避孕藥？
You think they have that morning-after pill here?
那東西很有用碾碎了摻在荷包蛋裡面
That thing works. Crush it up, put it in her omelette,
「嘿，寶貝，在床上吃早餐吧」小心一點總沒壞處
"Hey, baby, breakfast in bed." You can never be too safe.
哦，老天
Oh, God.
我把錢包丟了
I lost my wallet somewhere.
這些都算在一起？
All this together?
- 不，不- 是的
- No, no. - Yes.
他是好漢
He is the man.
- 一共多少？- 哦，再加上這個
- How much is it? - Oh. Plus this.
20.42美元
PHARMACIST: $20.42.
西瓜味
(WHISPERING) Watermelon.
妞都喜歡
Chicks dig it.
謝謝
Thanks.
下回見
See you next time.
祝你晚上過得愉快
PHARMACIST: Have a good night.
我真喜歡這些能量飲料
I love these energy drinks, man.
我簡直是在用能量飲料洗胃
I'm almost, like, kind of on an energy drink cleanse,
早飯時喝一罐中飯時又要喝兩三罐
where I do one for breakfast and then, like, two or three for lunch.
我是好漢？
WESLEY: I'm the man?
對啊，巴裡，我是好漢
(SCOFFING) Yeah, right, Barry, I'm the man.
事實上，我真是了不起的好漢
In fact, I'm so much the man,
要靠不停地吃藥來防止焦慮癥發作
I have a standing prescription for medication to control my anxiety attacks.
天哪但願有什麼別的東西能緩解我的壓力
God, I wish I had something else to relieve my stress.
你好，韋斯利
Hello, Wesley.
你知道，有些人，是美人
WESLEY: You know, there are people, beautiful people,
你只希望她們能在別樣的環境下別樣的地方看到你
you just wish they could see you in a different setting, a different place,
不是在這個鬼地方看你不是看你這副鬼樣
instead of where you are, what you've become.
妮可長得太贊啦
(WHISPERING) Nicole is so hot.
什麼？
What?
被她雷到啦
Boom goes the dynamite.
不過大多數時候你希望自己不是那麼廢柴
WESLEY: But most of all, you wish you weren't such a pussy
不該企盼不可能發生的改變
for wishing for things that will never change.
全能的好上帝啊你是在他媽的度春假嗎
JANICE: Good God A'mighty, you're over here like it's spring fucking break,
我到現在還沒拿到那份結算報告
and I still don't have that billing report.
我到底為什麼養你，韋斯利？
Why do I even keep you around, Wesley?
我會做完的，賈妮絲
I'll get it done, Janice.
好像我以前沒聽過這話一樣「我會做完的」
(SCOFFING) Like I never heard that before. "I'll get it done."
(HEART BEATING)
我會做完的，我會做完的我會做完的
"I'll get it done. I'll get it done, Janice.
我會做完的
"I'll get it done."
(INDISTINCT DISTORTED CHATTERING)
(HEART BEATING FASTER)
你就沒什麼要說的？
Why don't you have anything to say for yourself?
對不起
(DISTORTED) I'm sorry.
哦，你這廢物
Well, you're worthless.
我才應該說對不起因為我雇了你這蠢驢
I'm the one who's sorry I hired your ass.
(HEART BEATING RAPIDLY)
(HEART BEATING SLOWER)
(BREATHING DEEPLY)
知道一天結束時最妙的一點是什麼嗎？
WESLEY: You know what the best thing is about the end of the day?
明天又要從頭再來一遍
Tomorrow it starts all over again.
(ROCK MuSIC PLAYING)
無法處理您的交易
資金不足，你是個混蛋
你沒錢了你最好的朋友在操你女朋友
你知道，可是你這軟蛋什麼也做不了
(HEART BEATING)
- 嗨，你好嗎？- 很好
- Hi. How you doing? - Good.
- 對不起？- 你道歉次數太多了
- I'm sorry? - You apologise too much.
我很抱歉
Sorry about that.
我認識你父親
I knew your father.
我出生第一周，父親就跑了，所以…
My father left the week I was born, so...
你父親昨天在大都會大廈的屋頂上死了
Your father died yesterday on the rooftop of the Metropolitan Building.
對不起
Sorry.
(LAUGHS)
你看，酒吧就在那邊，所以…
Look, the liquor rounds are just over there, so...
你父親是有史以來最優秀的刺客之一
Your father was one of the greatest assassins who ever lived.
殺他的人就在你背後
The man who killed him is behind you.
(HEART BEATING)
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
別錯過
最後的機會
(HEART BEATING FASTER)
那傢伙亂開槍…
This guy's just shooting up...
對不起，對不起
Sorry. Sorry.
(ELECTRONIC BARKING)
(TYRES SCREECHING)
什麼… 哦，上帝！哦，上帝！剛才到底怎麼回事？
What... Oh, my God! Oh, my God! What the fuck just happened?
拜託！拜託！拜託你開快點
Please! Please! Please drive faster.
- 拜託你安靜- 拜託… 拜託開快點
- Please be quiet. - Please drive... Please drive faster.
請你… 請你明白我對自己的性命很在乎！
Please... Please understand that I care about my life!
我不知道你幹了什麼事把那傢伙惹毛了
I don't know what the fuck you did to piss this guy off,
可是你得讓我逃出去叫警察啊！
but you're gonna have to let me out and call the cops!
嘿！嘿！
Hey! Hey!
(SIREN WAILING)
你幹什麼？哦，操！你瘋了嗎？
What are you doing? Oh, shit! Are you crazy?
哦，操！
Oh, shit!
我看我們甩掉他了，我們甩掉他了
I think we lost him. I think we lost him.
在下一個街角讓我下車，好嗎？
Could you let me out at the next corner, please?
操！
Shit!
我操！
Fuck!
哦，操！
Oh, shit!
他就在那邊！
He's right there!
我是個會計，我只是個會計
Look, I'm an accountant. I'm just an accountant.
我操！
Oh, fuck!
他還真是死心眼
He's fucking persistent, you know.
我操！
Fuck!
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
給他點顏色瞧瞧！
You kick his ass!
打他！
Shoot him!
你幹什麼？你打自己的車幹什麼？
What are you doing? What are you shooting our car for, huh?
- 你瘋了嗎？- 抓住方向盤
- Are you crazy? - FOx: Grab the wheel.
你要去哪？
WESLEY: Where are you going?
回來！
Get back in here!
哦，上帝！
Oh, my God!
(WESLEY ExCLAIMS)
該死的！對不起
Oh, damn! I'm sorry.
- 槍！- 什麼？
- Gun! - What?
在座位底下！
FOx: Under the seat!
給
WESLEY: Here.
(HONKING)
(SCREAMING)
(FOx GRUNTS)
哦，操！
WESLEY: Oh, shit!
(SIRENS WAILING)
操！
Shit!
(HEART BEATING)
- 當心！- 讓開！
- WESLEY: Look out! - Get out!
當心！哦，上帝！
Look out! Oh, my God!
操！
Shit!
對不起！
WESLEY: I'm sorry!
(CHATTERING ON POLICE RADIO)
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
(SCREAMING)
在你後面！
OFFICER: Behind you!
(OFFICERS SHOUTING)
(ELECTRONIC BARKING)
(POP MuSIC PLAYING ON CAR RADIO)
(FLY BUZZING)
(GASPS)
我操
Fuck.
操，操
Shit. Shit.
(ExCLAIMS)
你好
Hello.
我沒有錢，也沒有…
I don't have any money or...
我還以為他的個子要
SLOAN: I thought he'd be
高一點
taller.
高一點？
Taller?
先生…
Sir...
先生，我一直在對這位女士解釋我是個會計
Sir, I've been trying to explain to the lady here that I'm an accountant.
我是賬戶服務代表…我是賬戶經理
I'm an account service representative... I'm an account manager.
要是你們打電話給我的老闆，賈妮絲
And I'm sure that if you call my boss, Janice,
她肯定會幫你們解決問題
she'd fill you in on whatever has gone wrong.
你們可以給她發電子郵件或者…她會幫你們解決的
You can contact her by email or... She'll put you straight.
把蒼蠅的翅膀打下來
SLOAN: Shoot the wings off the flies.
我不知道這是什麼意思
I don't know what that means.
把蒼蠅的翅膀打下來
Shoot the wings off the flies.
你們肯定是把我當成別人了
I really think you have me mixed up with somebody else.
(HEART BEATING)
我數到三
On three.
你不開槍，我就開槍
Either you shoot, or I do.
一
One.
好吧
Okay.
(HEART BEATING FASTER)
二
Two.
我連看都看不清！
I can't even see them!
(HEART BEATING RAPIDLY)
三
Three.
(GASPING)
好了，好了
Okay. Okay.
(BREATHING DEEPLY)
(HEART BEATING SLOWER)
這不可能
That's impossible.
在今天以前有很多事情對你來說是不可能的
SLOAN: A lot of things for you weren't possible before today.
韋斯利，你剛才體會到的並不是恐慌癥發作
What you experienced, Wesley, was not a panic attack.
你的心臟每分鐘跳了400多下
Your heart was beating in excess of 400 beats per minute,
使你的血液裡充滿了腎上腺素
sending abundant amounts of adrenaline into your bloodstream.
這就使你能比常人更快地觀察和反應
This allows you to see and react faster than normal.
全世界能做到的人只有區區幾個
Only a few people in the world can do that.
你父親能做到，你也能做到
Your father could do it and you can do it.
稍微鍛煉一下你就能學會控制這樣的發作
With a little work, you can learn to control these attacks.
離我遠點
Stay away from me.
你離我遠點
Just stay back from me.
我有槍，先生，明白嗎？
I have a gun, sir. All right?
我叫斯隆
My name is Sloan.
這位是狐貍
This is Fox.
在你周圍的其他人都是殺人高手
And the others you see around you are all very good at killing.
所以呢，如果我是你我會一直把槍指著我
So, if I were you, I'd keep the gun pointed at me.
用槍指著他們是沒有好果子吃的
You don't wanna point it at any of them.
你這樣比較好
That's better.
- 你是瘋子- 不
- You're insane. - No.
真正的瘋狂是：明明體內流著殺手之血
Insanity is wasting your life as a nothing
卻碌碌無為地虛度光陰
when you have the blood of a killer flowing in your veins.
真正的瘋狂是：心中關著一頭猛獅
Insanity is being shit on, beat down,
手裡掌握了釋放它的鑰匙
coasting through life in a miserable existence
卻甘心被欺侮、被打敗渾渾噩噩地過著悲慘的人生
when you have a caged lion locked inside and a key to release it.
你手裡的這把槍是伊瑪尼什17型它本來是你父親的
This gun you're holding is an lmanishi 17. It belonged to your father.
他可以用它演奏交響樂
He could conduct a symphony orchestra with it.
你將用它殺死殘忍地槍殺你父親的兇手
And you're going to use it to kill the man who shot him down in cold blood.
- 我不能…- 那天晚上想殺你的人也是他
- I can't... - The same man who tried to kill you tonight.
你父親是我們的一員
Your father was one of us.
我們是刺客兄弟會命運的武器
A fraternity of assassins. The weapons of fate.
我們已經把他的所有財產都轉到你名下
We've transferred all of his assets over to you.
我向你保證，數目非常可觀
And let me assure you, they are substantial.
這就是你等待了很久的命運
It is your long-awaited destiny
加入我們
to join us.
你退後，退後
Back off. Back off.
你對我一點也不瞭解
You don't know anything about me.
離我遠點，離我遠點
Stay away from me. Stay away from me.
你離我遠點
You stay away from me?
你離我遠點，好嗎？讓我過去行不行？
You stay away from me, please? Will you let me through?
(SCREAMS)
(TRAIN RUMBLING)
有時候做了一個夢，迷迷糊糊醒過來
WESLEY: You know when you have a dream and you're half awake,
那個夢仍然在腦海裡，揮之不去
but it's still in the fringe of your brain?
這時候你睜開眼睛發現那只是個夢，就會樂得打滾
Then you open your eyes and you're so damn glad it was a dream.
(CLANKS)
這一次可不是夢
This was nothing like that.
(HEART BEATING)
(HEART BEATING FASTER)
(TRAIN RUMBLING)
對不起，你等我一下好嗎？謝謝
I'm sorry. Could you just give me one second? Thank you.
哦，操
Oh, shit.
(SIGHS)
韋斯利
(WHISPERING) Wesley.
你怎麼了？
What's up with you?
你什麼意思？
What do you mean?
你… 你來得很早
You're... You're here early.
你… 你看起來精神很好
Is... You seem a little pepped up.
- 你好嗎？- 嗯，很好
- You all right? - Well, yeah.
很好
Yeah.
我覺得自己
I guess I feel
有點不一樣了
kind of different.
隨你怎麼說吧，我要去拿點報事貼要幫你拿一疊嗎？
Whatever. I'm gonna go get some Post-it Notes. Do you want one?
- 不用- 真的？
- No. - Really?
- 對- 好吧
- Yeah. - Okay.
黑幫在屋頂火拚五人被亂槍打死
天喲，地喲，親娘老子喲我到現在還沒拿到結算報告
Jesus H. Fucking Popsicle, I still don't have my billing reports,
你倒有閒工夫坐在這裡上網
but you've got time to sit here and Google your ass off.
哦，我知道一件事
Well, I know one thing.
下星期就要評審你的表現
You've got your review coming up next week,
我是巴不得早一點扣你工資啊
and I can't wait to start checking me off some big fucking boxes.
工作態度，差！績效，差！
Attitude, poor! Performance, poor!
(HEART BEATING)
管理能力，差！
Management skills, poor!
與他人的合作那是天大的笑話
(SCOFFS) Works well with others. That's a fucking joke.
(HEART BEATING FASTER)
這是什麼亂七八糟的？這傢伙是誰？
What is this bullshit? Who's this prick?
有幾個廢柴在大樓上被人爆了頭…
Some loser gets his head blown off at the Metropolitan...
閉上你的臭嘴！
Shut the fuck up!
她當了一個芝麻綠豆大的官
She has one single iota of tenuous power.
就以為可以把大家當傭人使喚
She thinks she can push everyone around.
你不需要這個
You don't need this.
我能理解
(SOFTLY) I understand.
國中的日子肯定不好過
Junior high must have been kind of tough,
可是這不等於說你有權讓員工做牛做馬，賈妮絲
but it doesn't give you the right to treat your workers like horseshit, Janice.
我知道大家都在笑你，賈妮絲
I know we laugh at you, Janice.
我們都知道你在辦公桌最上面的抽屜裡藏了很多果醬甜甜圈
We all know you keep your stash of jelly doughnuts in the top drawer of your desk.
可是我要告訴你
But I want you to know
如果你不是那麼招人厭我們會同情你的
if you weren't such a bitch, we'd feel sorry for you.
我真的有點同情你
I do feel sorry for you.
可是考慮到你的表現
But as it stands, the way you behave,
我覺得我可以代表整個辦公室的人
I feel I can speak for the entire office
對你說
when I tell you
吃屎去吧
go fuck yourself.
(WHIMPERS)
太強了，誰是好漢？
Yeah. That was great, bro. Who's the man?
去你媽的
我是好漢
I'm the man.
(ROCK MuSIC PLAYING)
攝像頭攝下嫌犯面容
通緝犯
(CHUCKLES)
這是個壞主意
That's a bad idea.
找不到你的鑰匙了嗎？
Couldn't find your keys, huh?
這一手可能很有用你會教我嗎？
That could be handy. You going to teach me that?
我也許用得著
I might need that.
你叫，狐貍，對吧？那是什麼？是代號嗎？
So, Fox, right? What is that? Is that a call sign?
就像《壯志凌雲》裡的「小牛」？
Is it like Maverick in Top Gun?
你要是告訴我真名，就得殺了我？
You could tell me, but you'd have to kill me?
我開玩笑的
(LAUGHING) I'm just kidding.
(ROCK MuSIC CONTINuES)
17號織造廠
(WORKERS SHOUTING)
彼得！
SLOAN: Peter!
檢查一下這台STB的梭子轉速應該是每分鐘300轉
Check the shuttle rotation on this STB. It should be 300 per minute.
這種棉織品的相反絲線應該是4000根
This kind of cotton weave, the opposing thread count should be 4,000.
嘿，真了不起
Hey, this is pretty awesome, huh?
這是幌子嗎？
Is it a front?
- 什麼東西的幌子？- 我不知道
- Front for what? - I don't know.
暗殺吧
Assassinations.
你也許以為這是用來掩蓋的幌子
You may think this is a front for something,
我只能告訴你這是一個紡織廠
all I can tell you is this is a textile mill.
喬治…喬治，去幫彼得一下
And George... George, go help Peter up there.
好
Yeah.
這是個紡織廠
This is a textile mill.
而且很不錯
And a damn good one.
哦，妙極了，不過那是騙人的吧？
WESLEY: Yeah, that's cute, but that's bullshit, right?
我是說，這些人都是殺手吧，對嗎？
I mean, all these guys are killers, aren't they?
我覺得你該回答我幾個問題
I think you owe me some answers.
好吧，我顯然是不懂
All right. Clearly I don't understand,
你們是做毛衣的還是殺人的？
but do you make sweaters or do you kill people?
(WORKERS STOP CHATTERING)
喝杯咖啡問了這麼多問題
That's an awful lot of questions over coffee.
你真的準備好聽答案了嗎？
Are you sure you're ready for the answers?
是的
Yes, I'm sure.
我沒法回頭了
I can't go back.
不可能回到原來的生活
Not to my life.
他歸你了
SLOAN: He's all yours.
好，咱們走
All right. We're up.
你好嗎？
REPAIRMAN: How you doing?
我是修補匠
I'm The Repairman.
你修補什麼？
What do you repair?
一輩子的壞習慣
A lifetime of bad habits.
- 好吧- 你幫我個忙好嗎？
- Okay. - Would you do me a favour?
把你的手臂放到身後
Just put your arms behind your back.
- 沒事的- 我不知道…
- It's okay. - I don't know...
- 放到背後- 這樣就行？
- Just behind your back. - Is this okay?
放鬆
REPAIRMAN: Just relax.
這也是訓練？
WESLEY: Is this part of it?
我們開始吧
REPAIRMAN: There we go.
- 你要在我頭上套個口袋？- 不，不用口袋
- You going to put a bag over my head? - REPAIRMAN: No. There's no need for a bag.
- 不會太緊吧？- 不，這樣很好
- That's not too tight, is it? - No, that's nice.
你為什麼來這裡，韋斯利？
Why did you come here, Wesley?
是你帶我來的，你忘了？
Well, you brought me here, remember?
你他媽的幹什麼…
(GROANING) What the fuck did you do that...
(HEART BEATING)
(GROANING)
修理工打了他幾下
How many punches did The Repairman throw
才開始數綿羊的？
before he was counting sheep?
以前我的臉被打的次數不多，明白嗎？
Well, I haven't spent a lot of time having my face smashed in before, all right?
- 你用刀的次數多嗎？- 早飯、中飯和晚飯時都用
- Did you spend a lot of time with knives? - At breakfast, lunch and dinner.
操
WESLEY: Fuck.
剛才那是個反問句，蠢驢
It was a rhetorical question, culo.
你要是再插嘴，我就用刀刃抽你
You interrupt me again, I use the business end.
他媽的，現在你聽好了
Here's what you need to know, puto.
刀子很容易隱藏
Knives are easy to hide.
它們不會卡殼也永遠不會用光子彈
They don't jam and they never run out of bullets.
(COUGHS)
如果你要做近距離接觸的工作
They come in handy
刀子是非常好用的
when you have to do some close contact work.
這是怎麼回事，老兄？
What the fuck, man?
- 過來，過來- 啥？
- Come here. Come here. - WESLEY: What?
- 現在，試著砍我- 什麼？
BUTCHER: Now, try to cut me. WESLEY: What?
試著砍我，喂！
Try to cut me. Hey!
- 就用那個戳我…- 你當心點，這刀很快
- Just stick me with that... - Be careful with that. That's sharp.
- 你就戳、戳、戳- 為什麼？
- Just stick and stick and stick. - Why?
- 說真的，老兄，我可能會弄傷你- 喂！
- Seriously, man, I could hurt you. - Hey!
好吧，娘娘腔
Okay, pussy.
- 我不是娘娘腔- 你就是娘娘腔
- I'm not a pussy. - You're a pussy.
- 不，我不是娘娘腔- 你就是娘娘腔！
- No, I'm not a pussy. - You're a pussy!
我不是娘娘腔我只是在意你的健康狀況
I'm not a pussy. I got a healthy respect for the human condition.
- 放屁，娘娘腔！- 我不是娘娘腔！
- Fuck that, you pussy! - I'm not a pussy!
- 你就是娘娘腔！- 我不是娘娘腔！
- You're a pussy! - I'm not a pussy!
- 來吧，娘娘腔- 我不是娘娘腔！
- Come on, pussy. - I'm not a pussy!
(ExCLAIMS IN PAIN)
(SCREAMING)
(MUFFLED SCREAMING)
嗨，你好嗎？
Hi. How you doing?
怎麼回事？
What the fuck?
操！
The fuck!
稍等一下，稍等一下
(HUSHING) Just a moment. Just a moment.
對不起
Sorry.
喂，喂！
WESLEY: Hello? Hey!
回來，喂！
Hey, come back! Hey!
你一定要喝下去，喝下去，對
You must drink. Drink. Yeah.
(COUGHS)
- 這是什麼？- 這裡是康復室
- What is this? - This is the recovery room.
這種藥浴可以刺激白血球，加快康復
This bath stimulates white blood cells and speed up the process.
在這裡，瘀傷、刀傷、骨折只要幾個小時就能好，不用等上幾天
In here, bruises, cuts, breaks heal in hours, not days.
你騙我吧？
You shitting me?
- 這是什麼？伏特加？- 對
- What is that? Vodka? - Yeah.
- 你是俄羅斯人？- 對
- Are you Russian? - Yeah.
起來
Get up.
這是槍匠
This is The Gunsmith.
他對槍械的瞭解比任何人都多他會教你怎麼用槍
He knows more about a piece than anybody, and he's gonna teach you how to use one.
- 你好嗎？- 很好
- How you doing? - Pretty good.
- 你知道嗎？塞爾查的腿斷了- 哦，真的？
- You know that Seltzer broke his leg? - FOx: Oh, really?
真的，斷了三處
GUNSMITH: Yeah, in three places.
- 怎麼會的？- 從大樓上跳下來摔的
FOx: How'd he do that? GUNSMITH: Jumped off a building.
- 那他還好吧？- 還行，不過傷勢挺重的
FOx: So, is he okay? GUNSMITH: Yeah. It's pretty bad, though.
哦，上帝
Oh, my God.
哦，上帝，這做得太像真的了
Oh, my God, you guys, that is so realistic.
他已經在康復室呆了三天
He's been in recovery for, like, three days now,
他們說還不能讓他出來
and they say they're not even gonna let him out.
哦，上帝
Oh, my God.
哦，上帝！
Oh, my God!
喂，我們不能開槍打死掉的女人！也許她是什麼人的媽媽…
Hey, we can't shoot a dead woman! She might be somebody's mom...
(GUN FIRES)
你必須瞭解子彈打在人身上是什麼樣的
You need to know what it's like to put a bullet in a body.
你為什麼來這兒？
FOx: Why are you here?
你知道，我以為我是來學習當超級刺客的
You know, I thought I was learning to be some kind of super assassin.
如果我想挨揍
You know, if I wanted to get beat up,
我就會呆在自己的小辦公室隔間裡了
I would have stayed in my cubicle, you know.
操
Fuck.
好，射靶子
FOx: All right, shoot the target.
從那裡射
From there.
- 你要我射穿死豬？- 我要你讓子彈拐彎
- You want me shoot through Wilbur? - I want you to curve the bullet.
我怎麼才能做到？
How am I suppose to do that?
你要問的不是怎麼做
It's not a question of how,
而是做什麼
it's a question of what.
如果沒有人告訴你子彈是走直線的
If no one told you that bullets flew straight
我給你一把搶讓你去射靶子
and I gave you a gun and told you to hit the target,
你會做什麼？
what would you do?
讓你的直覺來引導你
Let your instincts guide you.
他到底是怎麼做到的？
WESLEY: How the hell did he do that?
你能做到嗎？你能做到嗎？喂？
Can you do that? Can you do that? Hello?
嘿，我覺得那火車是我的老相識
Hey, I think that's my old train.
現在也是
FOx: Still is.
(SCREAMING)
操！你混蛋！
Shit! You fucking asshole!
來吧！
Come on!
咱們走
Let's go.
你是不是瘋了？
Are you out of your fucking mind?
哦，操，哦，操，哦，操，哦，操
Oh, shit. Oh, shit. Oh, shit. Oh, shit.
(SCREAMING)
哦，上帝，我覺得…我覺得…我覺得…
Oh, God, I feel... I feel... I feel...
我覺得有點爽
I feel kind of good.
他幹掉了裂嘴完美的一槍，不可思議的角度
GUNSMITH: He got Rictus. Perfect shot. Impossible angle.
十字架正在一個一個地殺我們
Cross is taking us out one by one.
韋斯利是唯一能做掉他的人
And Wesley is the only one who can get to him.
每過一個小時，十字架都會走近一步
Cross gets closer with each hour.
回去工作
Get back to work.
看見那個嗎？
FOx: See that?
- 那是個梭子- 對
- It's a shuttle. - Okay.
我要你想辦法抓住它
I want you to try and catch it.
你要我把手伸進去？
You want me to stick my hand in there?
對，我要你抓住它
Yes. I want you to catch it.
(SCREAMS)
(ExCLAIMS)
你要不要拿槍頂住我的頭？
You wanna put a gun to my head?
那樣的話我眼裡的東西就會像蒼蠅一樣變慢
I can just slow things down like with the flies.
你必須學會自己控制這種能力
You need to learn to control that by yourself.
(HEART BEATING)
操，操，操！
Fuck, fuck, fuck!
這是狗屎！我操！
This is bullshit! Fuck this!
韋斯利，今天好嗎？
SLOAN: How's it going today, Wesley?
不好，我操織布機我操修補匠！
No. Fuck the loom and fuck The Repairman!
我能打掉蒼蠅的翅膀！我已經準備好了！
I can shoot the wings off the back of a fly! I'm ready!
等到狐貍說你準備好了你才算是準備好了
You're ready when Fox says you're ready.
- 誰讓她負責的？- 我
- Who put her in charge? - I did.
(WHISTLING)
韋斯利
Wesley.
(CHUCKLES)
別人都以為要抓這些小美人得用奶酪
People think you use cheese to catch these beauties.
其實它們見到花生醬就會發瘋
But they go apeshit for peanut butter.
你父親特別愛玩這個，瞧
Your father was a big fan of this. Watch.
(WATCH BEEPING)
塑性炸藥和花生醬！
Plastic explosive and peanut butter!
對不起了，米奇
Sorry, Mickey.
五、四、三、二、一
Five, four, three, two, one.
嘿，嘿，俄國人
Hey. Hey, Russian.
這一隻很不錯
Good for one. Yeah.
要是有一千隻會怎樣？想想吧
Imagine if you had a thousand.
他們也狠狠地整過你，對嗎？
They really fucked you up, didn't they?
他們對你做過什麼？
What the hell did they do to you?
(WHISTLING)
無緣無故把你扔到高速火車上？
Throw you in front of a moving train for no reason?
打得你屁滾尿流？
Beat the shit out of you?
你知道，你可以說出來的這地方是狗屎，是狗屎，對嗎？
You know, you can say it, this place is bullshit. It's bullshit, huh?
狗屎！
Bullshit!
(WATER SPLASHING SOFTLY)
五分鐘以後，修補匠
Repairman. Five minutes.
你就不能警告我一下？
Heads up out of the question?
我操
Fuck.
你他媽的在浪費我的時間！你為什麼來這兒？
You're a waste of my fucking time! Why are you here?
我不知道，你打我吧
I don't know, so hit me.
- 你為什麼來這兒？- 我活得豬狗不如，為什麼不來這兒？
- Why are you here? - I had a shit life, so why wouldn't I?
我要好好揍你一頓！
I wanna kick your fucking ass!
告訴我吧，你要我說什麼？
Tell me what you want me to say.
- 你為什麼來這兒？- 我不知道！
- FOx: Why are you here? - I don't know!
你為什麼來這兒？
FOx: Why are you here?
- 你為什麼來這兒？- 我不知道為什麼來這兒
- Why are you here? - I don't know why I'm here.
你為什麼來這兒？
FOx: Why are you here?
Why are you here?
我不知道我是誰
I don't know who I am.
- 你說什麼？- 我說…
- What did you say? - I said...
我說，我不知道我是誰
I said I don't know who I am.
你真的想知道你是誰？
Do you really want to know who you are?
這是我的房間
Yeah. It's my room.
不
No.
這是你父親的房間
This was your father's room.
出了什麼事？
WESLEY: What happened?
兄弟會的一個成員造反了
SLOAN: A member of this fraternity went rogue.
十字架
WESLEY: Cross.
他一開始就殺了一個比他優秀的人
He started by killing the one man who was better than him.
你父親
Your father.
十字架在屋頂上偷襲他
Blindsided him on a rooftop.
背叛了他
Betrayed him.
這個房間裡的一切
Everything in this room,
書、武器、衣服
books, weapons, clothes,
都是他的
belonged to him.
現在歸你了
Now they belong to you.
在這個房間裡試著瞭解他，韋斯利
Find a connection in this room, Wesley.
也許只有靠這個方法才能弄明白你是誰
It may be the only way of finding out who you are.
現在我知道了為什麼我以前對什麼事都不在乎
WESLEY: Now I know why I could never care about anything before this.
我以前的生活是虛偽的
I was living a lie.
我終於有機會穿上父親的鞋子
Finally, I have a chance to step into my father's shoes.
我成了男子漢過上了我天生該過的生活
Grow a pair. Live the life I was born to live.
我之前還一直在逃避它把它當成了又一份該死的結算報告
I've been pissing it all away like it was another fucking billing report.
我應該更努力地訓練
I have to train harder.
我要和父親一樣優秀
I have to be as good as my father.
韋斯利，這些架子上放的是兄弟會的刺殺記錄
On these shelves, Wesley, are the records of the Fraternity kills,
要殺你的目標所有的信息都可以在這裡找
everything you will need to kill your target.
要殺十字架
WESLEY: To kill Cross,
要殺那個背叛兄弟會、殺害我父親的人我必須做好準備
the man who betrayed the Fraternity and murdered my father, I must prepare.
我必須成為他的學生記住他的每一次行動
I have to become his student, memorise every move he ever made,
他的每一次刺殺
every attack he ever executed.
他曾經在被特勤局特工包圍的密閉房間裡殺掉了一個病人
When he dropped a patient in an airtight room surrounded by Secret Service agents.
他曾經在電梯裡幹掉了那個商人
When he took out that businessman in the elevator.
當然了，他的子彈是無跡可尋的
His bullets untraceable, of course.
不管他消滅目標時用的是什麼武器什麼方法
Or how no matter what the weapon or how he eliminated his target,
他總是棋高一著
he was always one chess move ahead.
多留一手
One move more prepared.
先到一步
One step quicker.
先中一槍
One shot more precise.
事實上，我研究了那麼多材料發現他在殺人時從不失手
In fact, in all my research, I found that he never missed a target.
除了殺我那次
Not until me.
韋斯利，你這輩子第一次能控制了
First time in your life, Wesley, you're in control.
(GUN FIRES)
射靶子
Shoot the target.
你瘋了
You're crazy.
(HEART BEATING)
(HEART BEATING FAST)
(HEARTBEAT SLOWS DOWN)
歡迎加入兄弟會
Welcome to the Fraternity.
我們叫它天命織布機
SLOAN: We call this the Loom of Fate.
過了今天，你就再也不能走進這裡
After today, you will never set foot in here again.
為什麼？
Why not?
因為你就和耶穌的門徒一樣
Because, like an apostle,
你的任務不是闡釋，而是傳達
your task is not to interpret, but to deliver.
歷史上每一個文明都有一套密碼
Every culture in history has a secret code,
那是在傳統文字中找不到的
one you won't find in traditional texts.
一千年前
A thousand years ago,
一群織布工發現織物中隱藏著一種神秘的語言
a clan of weavers discovered a mystical language hidden in the fabric.
他們自稱為「兄弟會」
They called themselves the Fraternity.
跟你說實話，我只看見一根根線
I'll be honest with you, all I see are threads.
過來
Come here.
看那兒
Look there.
你有沒有看見有一根線織得不合規律
Do you see that one thread that missed the weave
蓋在了其他線上面？
and lies on top of the others?
- 這是出錯了？- 不，這是密碼
- Like a mistake? - No, it's a code.
如果垂直線在上，那就是一
If the vertical thread is on top, it's a one.
如果在下，那就是零
If it's below, it's a zero.
二進制代碼？
Binary code?
內容是什麼？
What does it say?
是個名字
It's a name.
一個目標
A target.
那些名字是哪來的？
Where do the names come from?
是因必要而產生的，韋斯利
Come out of a necessity, Wesley.
為了平衛這個世界的必要
A necessity to maintain balance in the world.
它們是必須被執行的命令
They are orders that must be executed,
我們被賦予在混亂中創造平靜的使命
entrusted to us so that we might forge stability out of chaos.
這個是你的
This one is yours.
我不…
I don't...
聽好，我以為你帶我來這裡殺十字架
Look, I thought you brought me here to kill Cross.
你會殺的
You will.
等時間到的時候
In time.
這是你的第一項任務
This is your first assignment.
紡織機提供任務
The loom provides,
由我解讀
I interpret,
由你執行
you deliver.
你要我去殺羅伯·迪恩·達登？
You want me to kill Robert Deane Darden?
不是我
Not me.
是命運
Fate.
目標將會在會議室裡坐在主席座上
FOx: The target will be in the conference room, sitting at the head chair.
總共有六個窗戶
There are six windows.
你會從第五扇窗戶射入
You will shoot through the fifth.
(CAMERA CLICKING)
第五扇窗
Fifth window.
現在
Now.
(GUN COCKING)
(HEART BEATING)
(HEART BEATING FASTER)
他做了什麼非死不可的事
WESLEY: What did he do that he deserves to die?
你不知道
You don't know.
我不知道他做了什麼壞事也不知道他有多邪惡
I don't know if he was bad, I don't know if he was evil.
我對他一無所知
I don't know anything about him.
我們從紡織機接收命令
We get our orders from a loom.
命運
Fate.
我們只能盲目地相信自己做的是對的
And we're supposed to take it on faith that what we're doing is right.
去殺我們根本不知道的人
Killing someone we know nothing about,
我不知道我能不能做到
I don't know if I can do that.
大約20年前
About 20 years ago,
有一個女孩
there was this girl.
她爸爸是聯邦法官
Her dad was a federal judge,
所以她大概從小就認為自己長大也會當法官
so she probably had it in her mind that she was gonna follow in his footsteps.
有一次她回家過聖誕節
So she's home one Christmas,
她爸爸正在辦一件詐欺案
and her dad's on this big racketeering case.
被告想要換個較心軟的法官
The defendants want to get a softer judge.
可以被他們收買的法官
One they can buy off.
所以他們僱用了一個人
So they hire this guy,
這個人叫做麥克斯·佩特裡吉
Max Petridge,
讓他去拜訪她爸爸
get him to pay her father a visit.
而他拜訪人的方法
And the way he pays people a visit
就是闖入對方家裡
is to break in
(INAUDIBLE)
綁起他的家人
And tie up their loved ones,
然後強迫他們看
and force them to watch
他活活燒死他的目標
while he burns his targets alive.
然後他會拿鐵絲製衣架把它捲起來
And then he takes a wire hanger and twists it round
把他名字的簡寫烙印在他們身上讓他們永生難忘
and brands his initials into each one of them so they will never ever forget.
我被吸收進兄弟會後
After I was recruited into the Fraternity,
在那聯邦法官被殺之前幾個禮拜
I found out that Max Petridge's name had come up
麥克斯·佩特裡吉的名字就出現過
weeks before the federal judge was killed,
但當時的兄弟會成員卻下不了手殺他
and that a Fraternity member had failed to pull the trigger.
我不知道我們做的決定對未來的影響有多深遠
We don't know how far the ripples of our decisions go.
也許你殺一個人
You kill one, and maybe,
可以救一千人
save a thousand.
那就是兄弟會的法規
That's the code of the Fraternity.
那正是我們所相信的所以我們才做這些事
That's what we believe in, and that's why we do it.
現在！
Now!
十字架
Cross.
還沒
Not yet.
你的目標將會在一台黑色豪華轎車裡
FOx: Your target will be in a black limo.
他的車會在哈士德路上行經六個路口
He always travels the same six blocks of Halsted.
你有三個路口的時間殺他
You have three blocks to kill him.
(HONKING)
(OPERA PLAYING ON CAR RADIO)
(GUNSHOTS)
媽的
Shit.
(HONKING)
對不起
I'm sorry.
巴裡！你能餵下安娜蓓爾嗎？
CATHY: Barry! Could you feed Annabelle?
巴裡！
Barry!
韋斯利，你跑哪去了？我很想念你，老弟
Wesley. Hey, where have you been? I have really missed you, man.
瞧你這好漢操你媽的混蛋！怎麼？
Look at the big man. You fucking asshole! What?
怎麼？你失蹤了幾個禮拜
What? You don't show up for weeks,
現在只是來借個廁所？
now you're just gonna stop by and use the bathroom?
你以為你是什麼大人物了，是吧？
You think you're a real big shot now, huh?
不，你知道嗎？你什麼屁都不是！
No. You know what? You are nothing!
不，你連屁都不如
No, you are less than nothing.
你比半個巴裡都不如
You're not even half the man that Barry is.
巴裡至少能讓我享受到你想像不到的快樂！
Barry, he pleases me in ways that you've never even heard of!
她是誰，韋斯利？你的新婊子？
Who the hell is she, Wesley? Your new whore?
你墮落到這種程度？需要花錢買了？
Is that what it takes now? You're paying for it?
(HEART BEATING)
韋斯利？
Wesley?
他是好漢
He's the man.
- 你還好嗎？- 還好
- You all right? - Yeah.
- 我沒事- 坐下，我幫你找台車
- Yeah. I'm okay. - Go sit down. I'm gonna find a car.
今晚很重要，我必須去康復室
Big night. I got to get into recovery.
(RATS SQUEAKING)
(CHUCKLING)
媽的
Shit.
操！
Fuck!
(HONKING)
(GUN CLICKS)
(HEART BEATING)
(HEART BEATING FASTER)
(HEART BEATING RAPIDLY)
(HEART BEATING SLOWER)
(BREATHING DEEPLY)
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
(GUN COCKING)
正中紅心
Bull's -eye.
他在這幹嘛？
REPAIRMAN: What's he doing here?
(GUNSHOTS)
- 拜託！- 拜託，振作點
- FOx: Come on! - Come on. Just stay with us.
把他的夾克拉下
FOx: Pull back his jacket.
(COUGHING)
呼吸，呼吸
REPAIRMAN: Breathe. Breathe, all right?
(GASPING)
沒事的，沒事的，沒事的
FOx: It's all right. It's all right. It's all right.
一千
A thousand.
拜託！
REPAIRMAN: Come on!
- 拜託！- 不！不！別死
- Come on! - FOx: No! No! Stay with us.
- 拜託- 張開你的眼睛！
- Come on. - GUNSMITH: Open your eyes!
快呀！
REPAIRMAN: Come on!
拜託！
FOx: Come on!
Come on!
(GROANING)
這顆子彈是他使用過的第一顆能夠追蹤到來源的子彈
This bullet is the first traceable bullet he's ever used.
是這個人製造的他叫沛克華斯基
It was made by this man. His name is Pekwarsky.
他的工作地點在東摩拉維亞修道院
He works out of what is now a monastery in Eastern Moravia.
這地方是兄弟會的誕生地
This place is where the Fraternity was born.
他在向我挑釁
He's taunting me.
他在傳輸一道訊息給我
He's sending me a message.
我也要傳個訊息回去
I'm gonna send him one back.
他對你設了陷阱
He's trapping you.
引誘你到他的地盤
Leading you to a place he knows very well.
這些我都知道，我…
Look, I know this. I...
你訓練我就是為了這個
This is what you trained me for.
你不能單獨行動
You can't go alone.
如果我不單獨去他就不會出現他可不是笨蛋
I go alone or he doesn't show. He's not stupid.
聽好，兄弟會的一個成員因我而死
Look, a member of the Fraternity is dead because of me.
好吧
SLOAN: Okay.
去吧
Go.
謝謝
Thank you.
我不認為那是個好主意
I don't think that's a good idea.
你的下個任務
Your next assignment.
沛克華斯基？
Pekwarsky?
媽的
WESLEY: Shit.
你在這幹嘛？
What are you doing here?
(GUN COCKING)
把你的槍放下
FOx: Lower your gun.
(SIGHS)
你知道這東西？
WESLEY: You recognise this?
這是從我肩膀裡取出來的
I pulled this out of my shoulder.
把它弄到我肩膀裡的人就是殺我爸爸的人
The guy who put it there killed my father.
我知道子彈是你製造的告訴我他在哪裡
Now, I know you made it, so tell me where he is.
子彈的確是我做的但我不能為使用它的人負責
I did mould this, but I can't be responsible for the people who use them.
我不管，告訴我他在哪裡
I don't give a shit. Tell me where he is.
看看我的手指
Look at my finger.
我可以試著讓你們會面
I can try and arrange a meet.
(WOMAN CHATTERING ON PA IN LOCAL LANGuAGE)
你有沒有想過過不同的生活？
Have you ever thought about doing things differently?
什麼意思？
How do you mean?
不知道
I don't know.
做另一個人
Being somebody else.
一個平凡人
Somebody normal.
沒有
No.
(WOMAN ExCLAIMS)
媽的
Shit.
閃開！
WESLEY: Out of the way!
(HEART BEATING)
(HEART BEATING FASTER)
(SPEAKING LOCAL LANGUAGE)
別動
Stay.
嘿！
Hey!
他在火車上
He's on the train.
他單獨一人
He's alone.
謝謝
CROSS: Thank you.
(ExCLAIMS)
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
對不起，對不起坐下！
Sorry. I'm sorry. Sit down!
先生，坐下！沒人會受傷
Sir, sit down! Nobody's gonna get hurt.
先生，坐…坐下！先生，坐下！
Sir, sit... Sit down! Sir, sit down!
(HONKING)
閃開！坐下！坐下！坐下！
Get out of the way! Sit down! Stay down! Stay down!
坐下！沒事！坐下！
Stay down! It's okay! Sit down!
(WOMAN SCREAMING)
韋斯利
(WHISPERING) Wesley.
閃開！閃開！
Out of the way! Out of the way!
(SCREAMING)
(BULLETS RICOCHETING)
不，不，不！
WESLEY: No, no, no!
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
韋斯利，聽我說
Wesley, listen to me.
閉嘴！
Shut the fuck up!
你不配跟我說話
You don't get to talk to me.
他們告訴你的都是謊言
Everything they told you was a lie.
閉嘴，你他媽的騙人閉上你的鳥嘴
Shut up, you lying piece of shit. You shut the fuck up.
你是我兒子
You are my son.
(GASPING)
你說什麼？
What did you say?
你剛說什麼？
What did you say to me?
(CROSS ExHALES)
是真的？
Is it true?
對
Yes.
你為什麼要我這麼做？
Why did you make me do this?
因為你是唯一他殺不了的人
Because you are the only person he wouldn't kill.
(SNIFFING)
你早知道了，他媽的
You knew, God damn it.
你從頭就知道
You knew the entire time.
他的名字出現了
Well, his name came up.
你的也是
So did yours.
(HEART BEATING)
不，沒關係，沒事
No, it was okay. Never mind.
不，不，這一切都是亂來
No. No, it was complete shit.
我答應了你父親把你帶回來這裡
I promised your father I'd bring you back here.
什麼？
What the fuck?
他說這是唯一讓你相信的方法
He said it was the only way you'd believe.
你爸爸一直都在你身邊
Your father was never more than a camera click away.
那是我
That's me.
他是我爸爸
He was my father.
而我殺了他
And I killed him.
對你父親來說保護你比自己的生命還重要
To your father, protecting you was worth giving up his life.
保護我？
Protect me?
他他媽的差點殺了我！
He was trying to fucking kill me!
不，他根本沒有要殺你
No. He wasn't trying to kill you.
他是在救你
He was trying to rescue you.
十字架離開兄弟會後
PEKWARSKY: When Cross left the Fraternity,
斯隆找到了你
Sloan hunted you down.
自從狐貍盯上你後他就一直試著把你從他們身邊分開
Ever since Fox had her teeth in you, he's been trying to separate you from them.
你爸爸從來不想讓你進兄弟會，韋斯利
Your father never wanted you in the Fraternity, Wesley.
他想給你一個不同的人生
He wanted a different path for you,
給你他永遠得不到的東西
with things that he could never have.
一個家
A home.
- 和平- 不
- Peace. - No.
他希望你能找到自己的前途
He hoped you would find your own way.
你爸爸找到了這個
Your father got hold of this.
你自己解讀吧
Decipher it yourself.
斯隆幾年前為了私慾開始自己偽造目標
Sloan began manufacturing targets of his own for profit years ago.
你爸爸得知了這件事
Your father found out about it.
他原本想要用自己的方法解決
And he was going to do something about it on his own, right?
但斯隆卻說服了所有人敵對他
But Sloan turned everyone against him.
我父親的名字從來就沒出現過，對不對？
WESLEY: My father's name never even came up, did it?
因為他遵遁規章反而讓他成了目標
No. Holding to the code made him a target.
斯隆
對
Yes.
- 你要我逃跑？- 不
- You want me to run? - No.
我想要你活著
I want you to live.
你可以過著不同的生活，韋斯利
You can have a different life, Wesley.
就如你父親所希望的
Like your father wanted for you.
我們把他訓練得很好
We trained him well.
我爸爸說錯了一件事
WESLEY: My father was wrong about one thing.
他們告訴我的並非全部是謊言
Everything they told me wasn't a lie.
他們教我如何殺人如何拋棄情感
They taught me how to kill, how to feel no pain,
最重要的是所有的任務都有一個最完美的武器
and most importantly, that every job has a perfect weapon.
我就是那完美的武器
Well, I'm the perfect weapon.
而我現在卻要逃跑？
And I'm supposed to run?
不，我已經逃避了一輩子
No, I've been doing that my entire life.
所以我拒絕
So I say no.
我要殺了他們讓命運來決定其它的事情
I say kill them all and let fate sort out the mess.
(SQUEAKING)
殺了他
Kill him.
(SQUEAKING)
(PEOPLE SHOUTING)
他在這裡！
He's here!
(GUN CLICKS)
(WATCH BEEPING)
(SQUEAKS)
(HEART BEATING)
(PEOPLE SHOUTING)
(INAUDIBLE)
(GUN CLICKS)
(SCREAMING)
(WHOOSHING)
(SCREAMS)
(GUNSHOTS)
膽小鬼
BUTCHER: Pussy.
膽小鬼，膽小鬼
Pussy, pussy.
(BUTCHER ExCLAIMS)
膽小鬼，膽小鬼
Pussy, pussy.
膽小鬼
Pussy.
(KNIFE CLINKS)
(BOTH SCREAMING)
(GUNSHOTS)
(GUN FIRES)
斯隆！
Sloan!
我爸爸不是叛徒
My father wasn't a traitor.
這是個殺人命令
This is a kill order.
而目標正是斯隆
And it's got Sloan's name on it.
你說過什麼？
What did you say to me?
是個名字，是個目標
It's a name. It's a target.
我不想要他死
I don't want this person dead.
是命運要他死
Fate does.
命運要你死
(LAUGHS) Fate wanted you dead.
他無法接受
And he couldn't take it.
所以他開始偽造一些目標來圖利
So he started manufacturing his own targets for his own gains.
我爸得知了這件事而決定與他對抗
And that's when my dad found out and decided to stand against him.
而你就利用他的兒子
And that's when you sent a man's son
去殺了自己的爸爸
to kill his father.
你不是命運的剌客，斯隆
You're not an assassin of fate, Sloan.
你只是個能讓子彈轉彎的壞人
You're just a thug who can bend bullets.
是真的嗎？
Is that true?
事實是這樣的
Here is what the truth is.
你的名字出現了
Your name came up.
你的名字
Your name.
你的
Yours.
這房裡的所有人
Everyone in this room.
如果我當時沒那麼做
If I had not done what I did,
你們都已經死了
you would all be dead.
我救了你們的命
I saved your lives.
看看現在的我們比以往更加強大
Now look where we are. We are stronger than ever.
用我們的能力改變歷史
Changing the course of history as we see it.
我們自己決定目標
Choosing the targets we select.
將權力分配到需要的地方
We can redistribute power where we see fit.
這是強者生存的世界
The wolves rule.
弱者只能死去
Not the sheep.
如果你們認為必須完全遵照兄弟會的規章
Now, if any of you feel the need to follow the code of the Fraternity to the letter,
那請你們舉起槍
I invite you to take your gun,
放到自己的嘴裡，然後扣下扳機
put it in your mouth and pull the trigger.
那是韋斯利想要的
That is what Wesley demands.
否則
Otherwise,
殺了這他媽的混蛋
shoot this motherfucker
讓我們把兄弟會殺手帶上前所未有的高度
and let us take our Fraternity of Assassins to heights
一個只適合神的高度
reserved only for the gods of men.
你的選擇
You choose.
去他媽的規章
Fuck the code.
(HEART BEATING)
(HEART BEATING FASTER)
斯隆！
Sloan!
(HEART BEATING RAPIDLY)
斯隆！
Sloan!
(HEART BEATING SLOWER)
六個禮拜前我只是個平凡無奇的人
WESLEY: Six weeks ago, I was ordinary and pathetic.
就像你
Just like you.
但現在呢？
But who am I now?
是帳戶經理？
Account manager?
殺手？
Assassin?
或只是一個被利用來殺死自己父親的工具？
Or just another tool who was mind-fucked into killing his father?
我都是
I am all of these.
也都不是
And I am none of these.
我現在是誰？
Who am I now?
我並沒有達成我的使命
This is not me fulfilling my destiny.
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
我並沒有追隨父親的腳步
This is not me following in my father's footsteps.
我也絕對沒有拯救世界
This is definitely not me saving the world.
(GUN COCKING)
還想知道你是誰？
Still trying to figure out who you are?
這不是我
WESLEY: This is not me.
這是另一個他媽的圈套
This is just a motherfucking decoy.
操
Oh, fuck.
(GRUNTS)
這是我控制情勢
WESLEY: This is me taking control.
不被斯隆
From Sloan,
不被兄弟會
from the Fraternity,
不被珍妮絲，不被報表
from Janice, from billing reports,
不被人體工學鍵盤
from ergonomic keyboards,
不被劈腿女友不被假惺惺的摯友所控制
from cheating girlfriends and sack-of-shit best friends.
這是我再一次重新掌握
This is me taking back control
自己的人生
of my life.
你最近做了些什麼？
What the fuck have you done lately?